[{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"C","question":"1. An artist known as the “Master of the Small” form of this genre was popularized by a series of 44 prints published by Hieronymus Cock. A small Charon crosses the Styx at the center of a work in this genre by Joachim Patinir, who pioneered its “world” variety. Haarlem native Jacob van Ruisdael specialized in these paintings, such as his Jewish Cemetery. 12 works in this genre, one for each month, were created by an artist who also painted one of these works in which a fisherman, a ploughman, and ships ignore a small pair of legs emerging from the water. For 10 points, “the Fall of Icarus” was depicted by Pieter Brueghel in what sort of painting that primarily depicts natural scenery? ","answer":"ANSWER: landscapes [or “Master of the Small Landscapes” or Landscape with the Fall of Icarus] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"C","question":"2. When confronted by robbers, this religious leader declared himself “the herald of the Great King” and was subsequently pushed into a ditch. This man and his first companion opened the Missal three times to seek divine advice; that companion was Bernard of Quintavalle. A church at San Damiano was rebuilt by this man when he misinterpreted divine instructions to “go and repair my church.” A song by this man praises various creations of God, such as Brother Fire and Sister Water, and is titled “Canticle of the Sun.” This man received the stigmata from a six-winged angel and legendarily preached to birds. For 10 points, name this patron saint of animals who lived in Assisi. ","answer":"ANSWER: Saint Francis of Assisi [or Giovanni di Pietro di Bernardone] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"C","question":"3. This city’s fortress of Sacsayhuamán [“sawk-say-wah-MAHN”] was constructed by the Killke [“KEY-ke”] culture. Conflict over the jurisdiction over this city resulted in the Battle of Las Salinas, after which Diego de Almagro was executed. This city, built in the shape of the sacred puma, had its Coricancha temple stripped of gold in order to pay a ransom for its ruler. After leading resistance from Vilcabamba, Túpac Amaru was executed in this city. During a civil war, Huáscar was captured defending this city from the forces of Atahualpa, who had been imprisoned by Francisco Pizarro. For 10 points, name this capital of the Inca Empire. ","answer":"ANSWER: Cusco [or Cuzco] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"C","question":"4. At the beginning of one of his books, this author states his desire to invent the path to Galta as he traverses it, to “go to the end.” With Eliot Weinberger, this man analyzed nineteen translations of Tang Dynasty poet Wang Wei. This man wrote a biography of Sor Juana subtitled The Traps of Faith. This author of The Monkey Grammarian wrote about the “poem” and the “poetic revelation” in his Heraclitus-inspired work of criticism, The Bow and the Lyre. In his most famous essay collection, he analyzed the traditions of his home country, including “The Day of the Dead” and “Mexican Masks.” For 10 points, name this Mexican writer of The Labyrinth of Solitude. ","answer":"ANSWER: Octavio Paz "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"C","question":"5. This scientist's article “Planck’s Law and the Hypothesis of Light Quanta” was translated into German and published in Zeitschrift für Physik. This man is the first namesake of a distribution of indistinguishable particles that is contrasted with Fermi–Dirac statistics. This scientist names particles that are symmetric over particle exchange and only have integer spin. He is the first namesake of a substance that was first produced by Cornell and Wieman by cooling rubidium atoms, in which all the atoms occupy the lowest quantum state. For 10 points, name this Indian theoretical physicist, who, along with Einstein, names a “condensate” phase of matter. ","answer":"ANSWER: Satyendra Nath Bose "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"C","question":"6. A theorist from this country used the kick-dancing Tiller Girls to illustrate his concept of the “mass ornament.” Two philosophers from this country coined the term “culture industry” and wrote Dialectic of Enlightenment. A philosopher from this country argued that the modern ability to duplicate art causes works to lose their “aura” in an essay on “Art in the Age of Mechanical Reproduction.” A philosopher from this country explained one concept using a term translated as “sublation” and formulated a master-slave dialectic. For 10 points, name this birth country of Theodor Adorno, Walter Benjamin, and G. W. F. Hegel. ","answer":"ANSWER: Federal Republic of Germany [or Bundesrepublik Deutschland] (the “mass ornament” was theorized by Siegfried Kracauer) "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"C","question":"7. In a play set during this holiday, Nora delivers a stillborn baby and her husband Jack Clitheroe is shot. A woman in a poem that takes place during this holiday spent “her nights in argument / until her voice grew shrill,” yet she remains in the same “casual comedy” as a “drunken, vainglorious lout.” The speaker of a poem that occurs during this holiday recounts passing people with “vivid faces” with whom he exchanges “polite meaningless words.” This day, the setting of The Plough and the Stars, names a poem which repeatedly states “a terrible beauty is born.” For 10 points, name this holiday which names a 1916 Irish rebellion immortalized by W.B. Yeats. ","answer":"ANSWER: Easter [accept Easter Rising; or “Easter 1916”] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"C","question":"3. In the second movement of a piece by this composer, a repeated eighth-note quarter-note viola rhythm is marked to be played “always very loud.” This composer of L’estro armonico and two versions of Orlando Furioso wrote a set of pieces that include instructions like “the barking dog” and “the drunkards have fallen asleep;” those concertos are included in The Contest Between Harmony and Invention. For 10 points, name this Italian composer of The Four Seasons. ","answer":"ANSWER: Antonio Vivaldi [or Antonio Lucio Vivaldi] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"C","question":"9. This polity’s air force installed Prince Peter on the throne after his regent, Prince Paul, acceded to the Tripartite Pact. Collaborationist troops attempting to surrender to the British were instead returned to this country in the Bleiburg repatriations. Many war crimes were committed in this country by the pro-Nazi Ustashe [“ooh-STAW-shuh”] militia. The Tehran Conference cut off aid to this country’s royalist Chetniks in favor of the communist Partisans. After this country’s partition by Nazi Germany, Ante Pavelić was installed as the head of a Croatian puppet state. For 10 points, name this Balkan country whose World War II resistance was led by Josip Broz Tito. ","answer":"ANSWER: Yugoslavia [prompt on Independent State of Croatia until “Croatian” is read”] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"C","question":"0. Enhancing this technology was the initial motivation behind the receiver operating characteristic curve, as well as a specialized vacuum tube called the klystron. A cavity magnetron connected to an antenna, which was used in this technology to output energy in the microwave region of the spectrum, was developed by the British Royal Navy during World War II. The presence of a “hook echo” discovered with this technique may indicate the approach of a tornado. Modern uses of this technology include its “Doppler” form, which is used in meteorology. For 10 points, name this technology that locates objects with the help of radio waves. ","answer":"ANSWER: radar [or radio detection and ranging; or Doppler radar; or weather radar; prompt on object detection; prompt on radio wave electronics or RF before “radio”] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"C","question":"1. A poem set in this city describes “philosophers who cry, ‘All is well,’ / And contemplate the ruins of this world.” While traveling to this city, an Anabaptist named Jacques drowns trying to save an ungrateful sailor from a storm. The title character of a novella is captured by the Inquisition in this city and sentenced to be executed in an auto-da-fé, but is able to save Cunegonde after he kills Don Issachar and the Grand Inquisitor. A catastrophe in this city teaches teaches a character to doubt Dr. Pangloss’s belief that we live in “the best of all possible worlds.” Voltaire’s Candide witnesses the 1755 earthquake in, for 10 points, what Portuguese city? ","answer":"ANSWER: Lisbon "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"C","question":"2. In the Ramayana, Guha uses one of these vehicles to help transport Rama in his journey. The giantess Hringhorni helps move an enormous one of these items during Baldr’s funeral. One of these vehicles made entirely from nails, known as Naglfar, will be set free during Ragnarok. The Norse god Freyr owns one of these vehicles called Skidbladnir that can be folded into his pocket at will. Zeus orders Calypso to help Odysseus build one of these vehicles that allows him to return home to Ithaca. The king Aegeus jumps to his death after his son Theseus forgets to change the black sails on one of these vehicles. For 10 points, name these vehicles that travel over water. ","answer":"ANSWER: boats [or ships; or ferries] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"C","question":"3. Dioxane and trioxane are both cyclic ethers with this many members in their rings. The Diels–Alder reaction reacts a diene and a dienophile to form a ring with this many members. Piperidine is a heterocyclic ring with this many members. Applying Hückel’s rule where n equals one corresponds to a system with this many pi-electrons. A cyclic compound with this many carbons exists in “half chair” and “twist boat” conformations. August Kekulé deduced the structure of a compound with this many carbons through a dream with a snake eating its own tail. For 10 points, name this number of carbons in benzene and cyclohexane. ","answer":"ANSWER: six "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"C","question":"4. In his Memoirs Illustrating the History of this group, Augustin Barruel claimed this group was an Illuminati plot to overthrow Christianity. George Canning published a newspaper opposed to this group, whose even purer Black proponents title a history of the Haitian Revolution by C.L.R. James. A journalist who supported this faction was assassinated by Charlotte Cordray. This faction controlled the Committee of Public Safety until their Reign of Terror was ended by the Thermidorian Reaction. The Girondins were opposed by, for 10 points, what radical faction of the French Revolution led by Maximilien Robespierre? ","answer":"ANSWER: Jacobins [or the Jacobin Club; or The Black Jacobins; or Memoirs Illustrating the History of Jacobinism] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"C","question":"5. The art of comic book artist Charles Burns inspired a 1991 production of this ballet by Mark Morris set in the 1960s. In a scene from this ballet, a character sits on a clock that begins to strike midnight, causing a tree to grow much taller. Divertissements stereotypically representing ethnic foods like Arabian coffee and Chinese tea precede the grand pas de deux [“pah-day-DO”]that bookends this ballet, which consists of a tarantella and a dance accompanied by the celesta. Notable excerpts from this ballet include the “Waltz of the Snowflakes” and the “Dance of the Sugar Plum Fairy.” For 10 points, name this Pyotr Tchaikovsky ballet traditionally performed around Christmas. ","answer":"ANSWER: The Nutcracker "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"C","question":"6. This character’s girlfriend sarcastically asks “what part of Long Island are you from?” and says “dating you was like dating a stairmaster” while breaking up with him. In the last scene of the film, a lawyer played by Rashida Jones tells this character “you aren’t an asshole. You’re just trying so hard to be.” Erica Albright breaks up with this man because he is obsessed with joining one of Harvard’s final clubs. A David Fincher adaptation of Ben Ezrich’s The Accidental Billionaires ends with this man settling lawsuits with Eduardo Saverin and the Winklevoss twins. Jesse Eisenberg portrayed, for 10 points, what protagonist of The Social Network and CEO of Facebook? ","answer":"ANSWER: Mark Zuckerberg [accept either] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"C","question":"7. The “sheepskin effect” describes an increase in this quantity, which is calculated using an equation named for Jacob Mincer. Research by Berkeley’s David Card suggests that immigration has little effect on this quantity; Card also studied the effects of increasing this quantity at various locations in New Jersey. Nominal rigidity refers to a situation in which this quantity become “sticky” or doesn’t react to market conditions. This quantity is often equated to the marginal product of labor. This quantity naturally decreases to a lower bound, according to David Ricardo’s “iron law” of this quantity. For 10 points, the federal “minimum” for what quantity is currently set at $7.25 an hour? ","answer":"ANSWER: wages [or incomes; or minimum wage] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"C","question":"8. These proteins include regions consisting of repeating sequences of asparagine, proline, and alanine, called NPA regions. A lack of these proteins in the distal collecting duct is a hallmark of many forms of diabetes insipidus. The activation of V2 receptors by antidiuretic hormone stimulates the insertion of these proteins into the cells of the kidney. These proteins typically consist of six alpha-helices that span the cell membrane. Peter Agre discovered that these proteins facilitate osmosis across the phospholipid bilayer. For 10 points, name these proteins that selectively allow the transport of water molecules. ","answer":"ANSWER: aquaporins [prompt on water channels] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"C","question":"9. Settlers in this colony were referred to as “long knives” by the Iroquois. Natives were educated at Brafferton in this colony after it signed the Treaty of Middle Plantation. This colony’s militia fought the Shawnee at the Battle of Point Pleasant; earlier in this colony’s history, frontiersman disgruntled by Doeg [“doog”] raids formed a militia and burned down its capital. Lord Dunmore and William Berkeley once governed this colony, whose earliest settlers alleviated the Starving Time by trading with the Powhatan Confederacy. For 10 points, name this colony where Nathaniel Bacon’s rebellious army marched on Williamsburg and Jamestown. ","answer":"ANSWER: Virginia "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"C","question":"0. In a chapter titled “[this place] Says Goodbye,” a character with “sad brown shoes” describes going away to this place so she can come back for “the ones who cannot.” In order to play in the “Monkey Garden” behind this place, Sally is told she must kiss a group of boys. After Lucy and Rachel are harassed, they hide high heels in a bushel basket behind this place. A tree behind this place is used for the First Annual Tarzan Jumping Contest, which Meme [“MEH-may”] Ortiz wins. Mama and Papa refer to this place as “temporary” when speaking with the young Esperanza Cordero. For 10 points, name this home in Chicago that titles a book by Sandra Cisneros. ","answer":"ANSWER: The House on Mango Street [or 4006 Mango Street; prompt on Chicago until mentioned] Tiebreaker. A victory in battle for these people was commemorated on the Day of the Vow, which has since been renamed the Day of Reconciliation. These people, many of whom died in the Weenen Massacre, formed a republic under the terms of the Sand River Convention. The murder of Piet Retief [“PEET reh-TEEF”] and his followers by Dingane [“DING-uh-nuh”] was avenged at the Battle of Blood River by some of these people under the command of Andries Pretorius. These people embarked on the Great Trek and migrated to the Transvaal, where they were later led by Paul Kruger. For 10 points, name these descendants of Dutch settlers who fought two wars with Britain in South Africa. "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"C","question":"[10] Elizabeth Vestris is credited with originating a design of three walls and a proscenium arch named for this shape. Loges, special seating areas in a theatre, are named for this shape, as is the “office” where one buys tickets. ","answer":"ANSWER: boxes "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"C","question":"[10] An influential American stage designer with this surname parted from realism in books like The Dramatic Imagination. An architect with this surname worked on masques with Ben Jonson before planning Covent Garden. ","answer":"ANSWER: Jones [or Robert Edmond Jones; or Inigo Jones] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"C","question":"[10] Stage designer Es Devlin, who has collaborated with artists like Kanye West, designed the closing performance for this event. Danny Boyle designed this event’s Opening Ceremony, which featured the “Chariots of Fire” theme. ","answer":"ANSWER: 2012 Summer Olympics [or Olympics in London; or the Games of the XXX Olympiad] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"C","question":"[10] Name this author who later responded to Meun in a work that details the accomplishments of over a hundred real and fictional women, titled The Book of the City of Ladies. ","answer":"ANSWER: Christine de Pizan "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"C","question":"[10] Pizan’s Book was inspired by this author’s On Famous Women. Marguerite of Navarre parodied this author in a work about five men and women who escape a flood by hiding and telling stories in an abbey in the Pyrenees. ","answer":"ANSWER: Giovanni Boccaccio (That Marguerite of Navarre work, The Heptameron, is a parody of Boccaccio’s Decameron) "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"C","question":"[10] Christine de Pizan’s works heavily critiqued the convention of the “courtly” form of this emotion. Ovid’s didactic treatise Ars Amatoria is typically translated as The Art of [this emotion]. ","answer":"ANSWER: love "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"C","question":"[10] Name this city. According to Ab Urbe Condita, it was founded by Romulus on April 21, 753 BCE. ","answer":"ANSWER: Rome "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"C","question":"[10] Ab Urbe Condita was written by this Roman historian, who also titles a set of Discourses by Niccolo Machiavelli. ","answer":"ANSWER: Livy [or Titus Livius Patavinus or Discourses on Livy] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"C","question":"[10] Livy was a tutor of this stuttering emperor, whose own scholarly pursuits included histories of Carthage and the Etruscans, as well as the introduction of three new letters to the Latin alphabet. ","answer":"ANSWER: Claudius "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"C","question":"[10] Name these events whose propagation was studied by Alan Lloyd Hodgkin and Andrew Fielding Huxley in the longfin inshore squid. ","answer":"ANSWER: action potentials [prompt on spikes or spike trains; prompt on impulses] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"C","question":"[10] Action potentials most commonly occur in these cells, which contain a cell body, axon, and dendrites. ","answer":"ANSWER: neurons "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"C","question":"[10] The influx of this ion into neurons provides the depolarization necessary to induce the propagation of action potentials. ","answer":"ANSWER: sodium ion [or Na+] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"C","question":"[10] Name this school of international relations, typically contrasted with liberalism, whose adherents emphasize the role of power in states’ interactions. Thinkers associated with its “neo” branch include John Mearsheimer and Kenneth Waltz. ","answer":"ANSWER: realism [or neorealism] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"C","question":"[10] To illustrate the security dilemma, defensive realists often cite the example of this early 20th-century war, which was partially caused by escalating tensions between the Allied Powers and the Central Powers. ","answer":"ANSWER: World War I "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"C","question":"[10] Robert Jervis claimed the security dilemma could only exist under this situation. The Constructivist Alexander Wendt claimed that this situation “is what states make of it.” ","answer":"ANSWER: anarchy "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"C","question":"[10] Name this King of Mercia who built a namesake dyke on his kingdom’s western border. ","answer":"ANSWER: Offa "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"C","question":"[10] Offa’s Dyke separates Mercia from this constituent country of the United Kingdom. The title “Prince of [this country]” is traditionally granted to the heir apparent to the British throne. ","answer":"ANSWER: Wales "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"C","question":"0. ","answer":"ANSWER: Edward I [or Edward Longshanks; prompt on partial answers] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"C","question":"[10] Name this son of Zal, the hero of the Iranian epic poem Shahnameh. ","answer":"ANSWER: Rostam "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"C","question":"[10] On Rostam’s first labor, he is completely asleep when Rakhsh, his animal of this sort, kills an attacking lion. Pegasus is a winged example of these animals in Greek mythology. ","answer":"ANSWER: horse "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"C","question":"[10] Rostam’s seventh labor involves killing the Div-e Sepid, known as the “demon” of this color. Zoroastrian priests wear robes of this color. ","answer":"ANSWER: white "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"C","question":"[10] Name this language. With Mandarin Chinese, this language titles a play about the mistranslation-hindered travels of American businessman David Cavanaugh in Guiyang. ","answer":"ANSWER: English [or Chinglish] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"C","question":"[10] This author wrote the aforementioned works Chinglish and F.O.B. French diplomat Rene Gallimard finds out that his “Perfect Woman” is actually a male Communist spy in this playwright’s M. Butterfly. ","answer":"ANSWER: David Henry Hwang "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"C","question":"[10] In this Amy Tan novel, Lindo takes English classes at the First Chinese Baptist Church with the other three members of the title mahjong playing organization. ","answer":"ANSWER: The Joy Luck Club "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"C","question":"[10] Name this ethnic group whose roughly 150,000 members live around the confluence of the Tigris and Euphrates rivers. Saddam Hussein attempted to destroy this ethnic group by draining their homeland. ","answer":"ANSWER: Marsh Arabs [or Arab al-Ahwar; also accept Ma’adan or shroog, even though these terms are considered derogatory] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"C","question":"[10] Marsh Arabs hold religious ceremonies in mudhif houses, which are made out of these things. Many scholars believe that the “Sea of [these things]” crossed by Moses and the Israelites in the Bible is actually the Red Sea. ","answer":"ANSWER: reeds "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"C","question":"[10] The Uru people live on “floating islands” made out of totora reeds on this largest lake in South America, which straddles the border between Peru and Bolivia. ","answer":"ANSWER: Lake Titicaca "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"C","question":"[10] Name this sandwich compound, which contains two cyclopentadienyl rings coordinated with a central iron atom. ","answer":"ANSWER: ferrocene "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"C","question":"[10] The two cyclopentadienyl rings in ferrocene serve this role. These compounds are Lewis bases that are coordinated to the central metal atom of coordination complexes. ","answer":"ANSWER: ligands "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"C","question":"[10] Ferrocene is also used as an antiknocking compound. Antiknocking compounds are generally used in this substance; they also help to increase this substance’s octane rating. ","answer":"ANSWER: fuel [or gasoline; or petroleum; or oil] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"C","question":"[10] Name this Chinese philosopher who argued for the existence of four innate ethical tendencies that he called “sprouts.” The last book of the Four Classics is this man’s namesake text. ","answer":"ANSWER: Mencius [or Mengzi; or Meng Tzu; or Meng Ke] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"C","question":"[10] Mencius may have been taught by Zisi, the grandson of this other Chinese philosopher whose teachings are found in the Analects. The rectification of names and five key relationships are concepts from this man’s teachings. ","answer":"ANSWER: Confucius [or Kongzi; or Kong Fuzi] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"C","question":"[10] This Confucian virtue is central to the Confucian concept of ancestor veneration. This virtue generally entails obedience to parents, and is exemplified by a Guo Jujing text describing 24 paragons of this virtue. ","answer":"ANSWER: filial piety [or xiào; accept hyodo or hiếu or oyakoko] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"C","question":"[10] Name this piece for piano and voice based on a Goethe poem. In this lied [“LEED”], the singer portrays a narrator, a father, a son, and the title character, all of whose melodies lie in different vocal ranges. ","answer":"ANSWER: “Der Erlkönig” [or “The Erlking” or “The Elf-King”] [10] “Der Erlkönig” is one of more than 600 lieder [“LEE-der”] composed by this German romantic composer. His never-completed Symphony No. 8 in B minor is nicknamed the Unfinished. "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"C","question":"[10] This Paul Dukas [“do-KAH”] piece, also adapted from a Goethe poem, uses the bassoon to represent the title character who disobeys his master. In Disney’s Fantasia, this piece plays as Mickey Mouse uses magical brooms to carry water from a well. ","answer":"ANSWER: The Sorcerer’s Apprentice [or L'apprenti sorcier] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"C","question":"[10] Name this conqueror who founded the Mongol Empire. ","answer":"ANSWER: Genghis Khan [or Chinggis Khan; or Temüjin] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"C","question":"[10] Despite his prohibition on certain ritual practices, Genghis Khan granted freedom of religion to his subjects in this secret law code, which was used to govern the Mongol Empire. ","answer":"ANSWER: The Yassa "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"C","question":"[10] This distant descendant of Genghis Khan commissioned the production of Islamic art in his capital city, Samarkand. This conqueror razed the city of Delhi, and was sometimes called “lame” due to his limp. ","answer":"ANSWER: Timur the Lame [or Tamerlane] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"C","question":"[10] Identify this electronics company named for a large U.S. state. ","answer":"ANSWER: Texas Instruments [or TI] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"C","question":"[10] While working at Texas Instruments, Jack Kilby invented the first one of these mass-produced semiconductor devices. They may contain billions of transistors in an area the size of a fingernail. ","answer":"ANSWER: integrated circuits [or ICs] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"C","question":"[10] The TI-83 Plus calculator included this type of nonvolatile, reprogrammable memory. “Memory sticks” store data via this form of memory. ","answer":"ANSWER: flash memory [or flash drives] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"C","question":"[10] Name this crop central to the play Kongi’s Harvest. In Arrow of God, a failed harvest of this crop convinces the people of Umuaru to embrace T.K. Winterbottom’s religion. ","answer":"ANSWER: yams "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"C","question":"[10] This Nigerian author of Kongi’s Harvest claimed “yams do not sprout amulets” in the poem “Abiku.” Olunde kills himself in place of his more wary father Elesin in this author’s play Death and the King’s Horseman. ","answer":"ANSWER: Wole [“WAH-lay”] Soyinka "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"C","question":"[10] The Yoruban word “abiku” refers to a dead one of these people. In Uzodinma Iweala’s novel Beasts of No Nation, Agu fights in the Sierra Leone Civil War despite being one of these people. ","answer":"ANSWER: children [or child soldier; accept clear knowledge equivalents like kid or boy] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"C","question":"[10] This President drew on his observations of the Autobahn as Supreme Commander of Allied Forces in Europe during World War II to authorize construction of the Interstate Highway System. ","answer":"ANSWER: Dwight D. “Ike” Eisenhower "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"C","question":"[10] A funding bill for this road situated entirely within Kentucky was controversially vetoed by Andrew Jackson, who allegedly did so to spite his Kentuckian rival Henry Clay. ","answer":"ANSWER: Maysville Road "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"C","question":"[10] The Camino Real [“rey-AWL”], or “Royal Road,” connects the colonial-era missions in California founded by this Spanish friar. He was canonized as a saint in 2015 despite opposition from Native American groups. ","answer":"ANSWER: Saint Junípero Serra "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"C","question":"[10] Name this quantity. Measured in amperes per meter, this property is defined as the amount of magnetic moment per unit volume. ","answer":"ANSWER: magnetization "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"C","question":"[10] The relationship between magnetization M and magnetic field H is not linear in materials exhibiting this phenomenon, creating a namesake loop. This phenomenon involves the creation of magnetic “memory.” ","answer":"ANSWER: hysteresis [or word forms] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"C","question":"[10] Hysteresis is observed in these kinds of magnets. This phenomenon, which exists in iron, nickel, and cobalt, involves permanent magnetic alignment and is named after iron. ","answer":"ANSWER: ferromagnetism [or word forms] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"C","question":"[10] Name this city where Pope Pius IV commissioned a Flemish artist to sculpt the grand Fountain of Neptune for the renovation of this city’s Piazza Maggiore. The fountain’s success led that sculptor to be nicknamed for this city. ","answer":"ANSWER: Bologna [also accept Giambologna] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"C","question":"[10] The aforementioned artist, Giambologna, quickly moved to Florence, where he painted an allegorical sculpture depicting “Florence Triumphant Over” this city. This city is the site of a famed Leaning Tower. ","answer":"ANSWER: Pisa "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"C","question":"[10] The work of Giambologna presaged this artistic movement in sculpture, employing its characteristic figura serpentinata. Benvenuto Cellini led the sculptural branch of this movement that featured exaggerated expressions and proportions. ","answer":"ANSWER: Mannerism "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"C","question":"[10] Name this most famous novel by Charlotte Bronte. A derogatory name for its character Bertha Mason titles Gilbert and Gubar’s aforementioned feminist study of Victorian literature, The Madwoman in the Attic. ","answer":"ANSWER: Jane Eyre "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"C","question":"[10] Madwoman in the Attic also discusses the work of a young Jane Austen, which is referred to using this term. This Latin-derived catch-all term for an author’s early works encompasses Austen’s Love and Freindship. ","answer":"ANSWER: juvenilia (yes, “Freindship” is supposed to be misspelled) "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"C","question":"[10] This novel is referred to as the “Bible of hell” in The Madwoman in the Attic. Nelly Dean relays the story of this novel to a disturbed Mr. Lockwood, who sees the ghost of one of its characters try to enter his room. ","answer":"ANSWER: Wuthering Heights (by Emily Bronte) "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"C","question":"[10] Name this Japanese religion whose shrines include the Ise [“EE-say”] Grand Shrine, which is dedicated to Amaterasu. ","answer":"ANSWER: Shintoism [or kami-no-michi] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"C","question":"[10] Statues of these animals are commonly found in Shinto shrines dedicated to Inari, the kami of these animals. Many East Asian countries depict these animals with nine tails. ","answer":"ANSWER: foxes [or kitsune] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"C","question":"[10] Shrine maidens called miko engage in a tradition referred to as kagura, which consists of this activity. A form of this activity performed alongside boiling water rituals at Ise Shrine led to a form of this called Ise-ryu kagura. ","answer":"ANSWER: dancing [accept word forms] Tiebreaker. Statins are drugs that lower the concentration of this compound by targeting the mevalonate pathway. For 10 points each: "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"C","question":"[10] Name this compound whose esterification can trigger the formation of foam cells. ","answer":"ANSWER: cholesterol "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"C","question":"[10] Cholesterol is important in maintaining the fluidity of this structure, which consists of a semipermeable phospholipid bilayer studded with channel and peripheral proteins. ","answer":"ANSWER: cell membrane [or plasma membrane; prompt on membrane] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"C","question":"[10] Cholesterol is an example of this class of compounds that consists of four fused rings, including three cyclohexane rings and one cyclopentane ring. ","answer":"ANSWER: steroids"}]
